JaimeDíez

Santander– Cantabria– Spain ☐ +34 649 004 985 ☑ jaimediezgp@gmail.com

SOCIAL

A Jaimedgp

in Jaime Diez Gonzalez-Pardo

0000-0001-7268-9933

♦ Jaime Diez

Mi interés por la programación me ha llevado a aprender varios lenguajes de programación de manera autodidacta a partir de proyectos personales que comparto a través de mi GitHub^O desde el 2015. Estas habilidades, junto con los conocimientos y capacidades adquiridas en mis estudios en física me han llevado a adentrarme en la ciencia de datos. Hasta ahora he podido poner en práctica estas habilidades en los distintos proyectos de investigación en los que he participado y en los que siempre he desempeñado un papel principal en el desarrollo de herramientas computacionales para la investigación tales como simulaciones, modelos predictivos o programas de adquisición de datos y que han llevado en algunos casos a la publicación de artículos científicos en revistas y congresos (ver mi ORCID [©]). Tras haber adquirido experiencia en el mundo académico me gustaría poder entrar a formar parte de una empresa en la que poder aplicar todos mis conocimientos y habilidades pudiendo adquirir experiencia en el mundo empresarial.

COMPUTER SKILLS

 $\begin{array}{c|cccc} & \text{Python} & R & \text{SQL} \\ \hline & C/C++ & \text{git} & \text{MatLab} \\ \hline & \text{Java} & \text{Fortran} & \text{bash} \\ \hline \end{array}$

Django Javascript
HTML CSS

LANGUAGE

Spanish English



FORMATIVE ASSESSMENT

HACK2PROGRESS IV edition

CIC Consulting Informático

Movember 16–17, 2018

Particle Physics Master Classes

IFCA, UC, IPPOG

March 19, 2015

Local phase of the LI and L Spanish Mathematical Olympiad

UC

₩ January 16, 2015

IV Prize Cantabria of Juvenile essay

Experience

Laboral

2020–2021 **Researcher**, *University of Cantábria*, Santander, Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering.

2018 External Intership, Intituto de Física de Cantábria, Santander, High Energy Physics and Instrumentation group. Main developer of MULTI-DAQ, a data acquisition software for an experiment of the measure of the muon life time in C++

Sports

2012–2019 **Handball Referee**, *Cantabria*, Top Regional Referee and several National-level Championships.

Vocational

2013–2016 **Caritas**, *San Jose parish*, Managing packing and distribution of food for families in need.

2016–2018 **Member of the Physics Mentor Group**, *Santander*, Group founder by students and aimed to help other students. Collaborated with UC in some activities.

Education

University Studies

2019–2021 **Master in Data Science**, *Universidad de Cantabria*, Santander.

2015–2019 Degree in Physics, Universidad de Cantabria, Santander, Mención en Física Fundamental. Including additional training in Computer Engineering's subject Databases

Pre - University Studies

2013–2015 **International Baccalaureate**, *Instituto Santa Clara*, Santander, High School Studies.

Studied simultaneously with "Bachillerato Nacional" and completed in two years following High School's schedule

SoCFia

₩ October 9, 2014

Astronomy Course

Observatorio Astronómico de Cantabria

₩ October 28–29, 2013